Child. Captive. Killer.
Beasts of No Nation is a drama, war film directed by Cary Joji Fukunaga.
Based on the experiences of Agu, a child fighting in
the civil war of a West African country.
Follows Agu's journey as he's forced to join a group of soldiers.
While he fears his commander and many of the men around him, his fledgling childhood has been brutally shattered by the
war raging through his country, and he is at first torn between conflicting revulsion and fascination.
Agu, played by Abraham Attah.
Commandant, played by Idris Elba.
Strika, played by Emmanuel Nii Adom Quaye.
Sergeant Gaz, played by Opeyemi Fagbohungbe.
Dike, played by Emmanuel Affadzi.
Father Friday, played by Richard Pepple.
Beasts of No Nation is a 2015 American war drama film written,
co-produced, shot, and directed by Cary Joji Fukunaga.
It follows a young boy who becomes a child soldier as his
country experiences a horrific civil war.
Shot in Ghana and starring Idris Elba, Abraham Attah, Ama K.
Abebrese, Grace Nortey, David Dontoh, and Opeyemi Fagbohungbe, the film is based on the 2005 novel of
the same name by Uzodinma Iweala, the book itself being named after a Fela Kuti album.
It was screened in the main competition section of the 72nd Venice International
Film Festival, where Attah won the Marcello Mastroianni Award.
The film was shown in the Special Presentation section of the 2015 Toronto International Film Festival, and
released on Netflix globally and in a limited release by Bleecker Street on October 16, 2015.
It is the first film to be released directly on Netflix.
The film received positive reviews from critics and numerous accolades.
Elba's performance earned nominations for the BAFTA, Golden Globe, Spirit, and
SAG Award for Best Supporting Actor, winning the latter two.
The film explores themes of guerrilla warfare, civil war,
based on novel or book, africa, refugee.
The tone is dark and emotional.